Christina Soulioti

SENIOR WEB ENGINEER

Profile

I have more than 10 years of experience in the field of .net ecosystem and Web Development.

Also involved in the front-end development of several web applications and have experience in **ReactJs** and all of its ecosystem.

Leading development processes, including planning, reviewing deliverables.

I am eager to be challenged in order to grow and improve my communication and professional development skills gained through reading books and technology related blogs.

Experienced with the latest cutting edge development tools and procedures.

Employment History

Front End Engineer, Schoox Inc., Thessaloniki

AUGUST 2022 - PRESENT

Lead Web Engineer, Ordereze, Thessaloniki

JANUARY 2015 - AUGUST 2022

- Lead development processes, including planning and monitoring efforts, coordination with other groups, reviewing deliverables, and communicating status with management.
- All of the developers in my team are adhering to the software quality standards agreed by my team and the wider development team so that work is done to the highest possible quality.
- Monitor, track and report on the status of projects and initiatives as required.
- To understand and be able to talk about and explain to my team the importance of principles of good software design and development so that we are able to produce software of the highest possible quality in the fastest possible time and will be able to continue to do so in the future.
- To act as an example to all the developers on my team by advocating learning and taking the time to do so myself so that they feel comfortable they can too.
- Follow the scrum methodologies in order to create better and faster results throughout the development process.

Technologies used:

C#.Net, Azure Cloud Services, Service Bus, Azure Functions, CosmosDB, SQL Server, Redis Cache, Azure Search, Application Insights, Azure DevOps, React Is

Business or sector: Online services and marketing platform specific to restaurant industry

Java Software Engineer, Intersalonica Group of Companies, Thessaloniki

NOVEMBER 2013 - DECEMBER 2014

- Design and development of the system for online pricing and payment of insurance fees.
- Design and development of web service which implements methods for create/update/edit of request for an insurance contract with the company.
- Design and development of an online application which implements the creation of a request for insurance contract.

Details

Thessaloniki

Greece

+30 6997233870

christina@csoulioti.com

NATIONALITY

Greek

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

29/11/1984 Athens

Links

csoulioti.com

LinkedIn

Github

Languages

Greek

English

Hobbies

Walking Indoor Rowing Painting

.Net Software Engineer, NLG Worldwide Gmbh, Thessaloníki

APRIL 2008 - OCTOBER 2013

- Design and development of the distributed reviewing system covering the whole review process, including management, review process and synchronization, automatic QA control and reporting of review projects.
- Mentoring and assisting the members of the development team.
- Implementation of agile methodologies and practices like Scrum and TDD.
- Design and development of the company's centralized translation memory system, that operated based on q-gram (n-gram) filtering and approximate string matching algorithms.
- Design and implementation of the authoring plug-in for Arbortext Editor written in C# based on Apache Lucene algorithm.
- Design, development and maintenance of multiple versions of client portals for various customers using ASP.NET and later ASP.NET MVC.
- Design, development and maintenance of the online review system that was integrated with other company systems using ASP.NET MVC and WCF.

Business or sector: Language Services Provider

Web Engineer, A.S.T., Thessaloníki

JUNE 2007 - DECEMBER 2007

- Design and implementation of various web sites using ASP, Vbscript.
- Microsoft SQL Server

Business or sector: Web Sites, Mobile Applications, SEO

Internships

Junior Web Engineer, Egnatia Odos A.E., Thessaloniki

JULY 2006 - FEBRUARY 2007

- Design and development of the game "Travelling to Egnatia Odos". This game aims at informing the users about various subjects concerning Egnatia Odos. It provides users with a tour of the cities Egnatia Odos passes through.
- Flash ActionScript, ASP, XML

Business or sector: Construction Company

Education

Master, University of Macedonia, Thessaloniki

OCTOBER 2007 - OCTOBER 2009

Master of Business Informatics

• University of Macedonia, Department of Applied Informatics, Thessaloniki

Bachelor, University of Macedonia, Thessaloniki

SEPTEMBER 2002 - APRIL 2007

Bachelor of Applied Economics

• University of Macedonia, Department of Applied Informatics, Thessaloniki

Extras

React Meetup Organizer, www.react-skg.io, Thessaloniki